演讲者1: 还有一个关于你最初设置重定向的方法的问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: And a question about the way
that you setup the redirect, initially.
我想我的问题是，我以前见过一个只针对客户的路线的例子。
And I guess my question is, I've seen
an example of client-only routes before.
如果有人使用的路由器库，我认为这是达到路由器。
Where someone used the router library
that's in, I think it's Reach Router.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 是的。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Yeah.
演讲者1: 相对于你在这里所做的，你设置了一个重定向
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Versus what you did
here where you set up a redirect
对其中一个或另一个的想法。
thoughts about one or the other.
Jason Lengstorf: 这是一种基于用例的东西
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: It's kind
of a use case based thing so
如果你使用达到路由器，你能做的是说,
if you use reach router,
what you're able to do is say,
根据我看到的 URL，显示一个不同的组件。
based on the URL that I'm seeing,
show me a different component.
这是一个很好的 API，但是在这个特殊的情况下,
And it's a really nice API but
in this particular case,
我们实际上想做的事情并不完全一样。
what we were actually trying
to do wasn't quite the same.
所以我们一直想展示相同的部分,
So we were looking at like, we wanna
show the same component all the time,
我们只是从网址中提取一些东西。
we're just pulling
something out of the URL.
如果 URL 是设置好的，那么我们就会显示不同类型的输出
And if the URL is set, then we're
showing a different kind of output so
没有什么对错之分，只是个案分析而已。
there's no really like a right or
wrong way, it's just a case by case basis.
Jason Lengstorf: 好的，现在 FEM 进度分支被推到了
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, so now the
the FEM progress branch is pushed up to
Github，已经完成了，我们今天所做的一切。
GitHub, it's done,
everything that we've done today.
而且你应该能够逐步提交，看看到底发生了什么。
And you should be able to step through
the commits and see exactly what happened.
在 GitHub 上还有一个叫 Chichi 的分支
There's also a branch on
GitHub called Chichi that
有链接到每个步骤之间的比较，所以
has links to comparisons
between each step of the way so
你可以看到代码一整天的演变过程。
you can see the code as it
evolved throughout the day.
还有其他问题吗？
Any other questions?
聊天有什么收获吗？
Anything coming from the chat?
说话人3: 如果我们使用的 API 需要一个 EMVA 变量,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: If the API that we
are consuming requires an EMVA variable,
你要在盖茨比配置中指定它们吗？
are you going to specify
them in Gatsby config?
如果是的话，它不会被发布到终端用户的浏览器上吗？
And if yes, it's not going to be
shipped to the end user browser?
Jason Lengstorf: 所以如果你想使用一个需要
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
if you want to use an API that needs
就像打电话的秘密一样。
like a secret to make calls.
你可能会想要研究一些类似无服务器的东西
You would probably want to look
into something like serverless
来处理这个问题。
functions to handle that.
因为客户端请求的条件是
Because the the catch with
client side request is that
如果你必须发送一个令牌沿，令牌将是可见的。
if you have to send a token along
that token is gonna be visible.
你可能会对这个请求嗤之以鼻,
You could be sniffed out of the request,
它可能从源代码中被剪掉了。
it could be snipped out
of the source code.
所以你可能不想这么做，但是如果你使用一个无服务器的函数。
And so you probably don't want to do that,
but if you use a serverless function.
你可以把电话中敏感的部分抽象出来。
You are able to kind of abstract away
the the sensitive part of the call.
相反，你可以说只有这个函数只能从我的域调用。
And instead you can say only this function
can only be called from my domain.
所以我的网站会向那个域名发出请求,
And so my website will make
a request to that domain,
通过呼叫限制或跨站点请求问题。
which passes the call restrictions or
the cross site request issues.
然后它会以你的名义发出认证请求
And then it will make that authenticated
request on your behalf and
把你需要的结果发回来。
send back the results you need.
所以这是一种保护这些凭证的方法，如果你有不真实的。
So that's a way to protect those
credentials, if you have unauthentic.
或者像不安全，像一个公钥，你需要通过,
Or like unsecure,
like a public key that you need to pass,
那么是的，你可以通过盖茨比的配置来设置它。
then yes,
you would set that through Gatsby config.
演讲者3: 同样的事情也适用于任何类型的认证吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Will the same thing go for
like any type of authentication?
我的意思是，一般来说，当你看到客户端的应用程序时。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: I mean, in general,
when you're looking at client side apps.
任何不应该被客户看到的东西都不应该出现在
Anything that shouldn't be visible to
the client probably shouldn't end up in
客户端代码。
client side code.
一般来说，如果你在《盖茨比》中用到这个词,
And as a general rule,
if you're working with it in Gatsby,
这是建造步骤，不是公开的，不会创造出艺术品。
it's the build step, isn't public
that doesn't create artifacts.
但是你要尽量避免把敏感数据
But you wanna try to avoid
putting sensitive data
任何类型的建造艺术品。
into any type of build artifact.
所以如果它开始反应如果它进入你的元数据或者类似的东西,
So if it gets to react, if it goes into
your metadata or anything like that,
你最好小心点。
you wanna be pretty careful about that.
它可以是有用的，只是不这样设置
It can be useful to
just not set like it so
作为一个例子，我们在 Gatsby 配置中设置了 Cloudinary API secret。
as an example, we set the Cloudinary API
secret in Gatsby config.
另一种方法，你可以处理真正敏感的东西
Another way that you can approach
that with really sensitive stuff
你可以说它需要在环境中存在。
is you can say it needs to be
available in the environment.
但是它实际上从来没有在配置中设置，代码只是期望,
But it never actually gets set in
the config the code will just expect that,
环境变量已经设定好了。
that environment variable is set.
这样就可以避免任何泄漏的可能性
And that would avoid it getting
any potential for a leakage or
这样的事情，所以如果你想真正确定。
things like that so
if you want to be really sure.
您只需确保它不会在任何配置的或
You can just make sure that it doesn't
gets set in any of the configured or
除了真正需要的东西，任何地方都可以使用。
use anywhere other than
exactly what's needed.
演讲者3: 那么认证模板和未认证模板如何？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So how about authenticated
templates versus unauthenticated?
所以身份验证模板，作为一般规则,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So authenticated
templates, as a general rule,
我的建议是不要预先建立，任何不应该公开的数据。
my recommendation is don't pre-build any
data that shouldn't be publicly available.
这意味着如果你有一个用户指示板。
So what that means is if
you have a user dashboard.
里面有任何敏感数据,
And that's got any kind
of sensitive data on it,
你不会想提前做好的。
You don't wanna build that ahead of time.
你不会想把这些都写进《了不起的盖茨比》的
You don't wanna put that into Gatsby's
因为任何静态资产都可能被泄露。
pipeline at all because any kind of
static asset can be compromised.
而且不这样做会更容易些
And it's just easier to not
try to play that game so
更简单的做法是让某人在 OAuth 工作流中登录。
what's easier to do is to have someone
login within an OAuth workflow.
然后，如果他们有一个有效的令牌并且
And then only send back that data
if they have a valid token and
只需在客户端异步完成。
just do it all on the client
side asynchronously.
演讲者4: 事实上我有一个问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Actually i have a question.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 是的，当然。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Yeah, sure.
说话人4: 关于服务器端的重定向。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Regarding
the server side redirecting.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 是的 议长4: 你在这里无效了，但是
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: You had nullified here, but
如果你用的是像 AWSS3这样的东西呢？
what if you were using
something like AWSS3?
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 你可以设置它，我已经做了它，我用什么,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: You can set it up,
I've done it and what did I use,
我想是53号公路，对吗？
Route 53, I think, is that right?
有一种方法可以做到这一点，我不记得我的头顶，但它是什么
There is a way to do it, I cannot remember
off the top of my head what it is but
你设置了同样的重定向。
you set up the same sort of redirect.
但我不记得 AWS 服务套件的哪一部分实际上处理了这个问题。
But I don't remember which part of the AWS
suite of services actually handled it.
但是如果你正在使用，比如你正在部署到 DigitalOcean。
But if you were using,
like if you're deploying to DigitalOcean.
或者另一种基于容器的服务，你可以使用 Apache 或者
Or another kind of container based
service, you would use Apache or
Nginx 建立这些路线。
NGINX to set up these routes.
像 nullfy 这样的托管服务倾向于使用基于配置的重定向。
Managed services like Nullify tend to
have configuration based redirects.
所以无论你去哪里
So anywhere where you're gonna
部署它最有可能，你能做到这一点。
deploy it most likely you'll
be able to make it happen.
这只取决于您的特定部署方式
It's just a matter of what your
particular flavor of deployment
需要重定向。
requires for redirects.
演讲者4: 我想我的问题，谢谢你
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: I guess my question,
thank you for
答案对我来说很明显你说对了,
the answer, it's entirely obvious
to me now that you said it right,
你必须做服务器端的配置。
you have to do the server
side configuration for that.
但是很多服务器就像如果它不能识别路径，对吧,
But a lot of servers will just like if
it doesn't recognize the path, right,
它返回像 HTML 一样的索引点。
it returns index dot
whatever like that HTML.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的 演讲者4: 你是不是有一个盖茨比配置
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: All right.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Is there a Gatsby config you
可以用在那种情况下，你知道吗，什么时候？
can use in that scenarios,
you know what, when?
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 这样的路线,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Well, so
the thing is with routes like that,
如果盖茨比只是为了这样的狂风暴雨而建立起来的话，你永远也无法了解盖茨比。
you'll never get to Gatsby so if Gatsby
is only set up for like slash surge.
那么文件系统中唯一存在的东西就是文件夹 / 搜索索引. html。
Then the only thing that exists in the
file system is a folder/search index.html.
所以服务器本身需要处理这个重定向，否则,
So the server itself needs to handle
that redirect because otherwise,
像盖茨比一样，我们必须公布每一条可能的路线。
like Gatsby, we would have to
declare every possible route.
每一个可能的角色组合来管理它。
And every possible combination
of characters to manage that.
我是说，这显然是不可行的。
And it's, I mean, that's obviously
gonna be very not feasible.
如果你使用无服务器,
If you're using serverless,
你不必站在一个有 NGINX 代理的数字海洋盒子上。
you don't have to stand up
a Digital Ocean box with a NGINX proxy.
它包装了为静态资产服务的节点服务器,
That wraps your node server
that serves your static assets,
这些问题就这么消失了，对吧？
those sorts of problems just
kind of disappear, right?
这并不意味着它们会消失,
And that doesn't mean they go away,
它们现在在别人的电脑上，而不是你的。
they're now on somebody else's
computer and not yours.
但是，这些服务正变得非常稳定和可靠
But the services are becoming
very stable and reliable and
这意味着我们作为前端开发商。
affordable which means that for
us as front end developers.
我们只需要把大量的问题转交给别人。
We just get to hand off a huge
number of our problems.
相信那些可能比我们在后台做得更好的人
And trust that someone who is
probably better at back end than we
都是用他们最好的方式做的。
are is doing it in the best
way they know how.
所以这总是有利有弊，但是
So there are always
trade offs with this but
对我来说这真的很令人兴奋，因为。
to me it's really exciting because again.
就像盖茨比从车前端拿走所有的锅炉牌一样,
The same way that Gatsby takes all this
boiler plate out of the front end,
果酱堆栈，无服务器。
the jam stack, the serverless.
而基础设施作为服务的东西，在那里消除了需要
And the infrastructure as a service stuff
that's out there is removing the need for
后面还有一大堆锅炉板。
a whole bunch of boiler plate
on the back end as well.
这就给了我们,
And that gives us just, I mean,
我们可以得到完全平等，与你过去必须建立。
we can get complete parity with
what you used to have to build.
一个成熟的服务器和
A full fledged server and
4加上几行 JavaScript 代码和一个无服务器的函数。
API 4 with a couple lines of JavaScript
and a serverless function now.
演讲者4: 对打字稿的支持---- 只有盖茨比会马上做到。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: TypeScript support,
just Gatsby'll do it out of the box.
有没有一个配置-Jason Lengstorf: 有一个插件和
Is there a configuration that-
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: There's a plugin and
它叫做盖茨比插件打字稿。
it's called Gatsby plugin TypeScript.
这应该会增加支持，就像配置一行一样。
That should add support,
like with one line of config.
我不是一个打字稿开发者，所以我不确定是否完全诚实。
I'm not a TypeScript developer, so
I'm not sure to be completely honest.